<!--
Copyright 2020 The Chromium Authors. All rights reserved.
Use of this source code is governed by a BSD-style license that can be
found in the LICENSE file.
-->

<!--
This file is used to generate a comprehensive list of Omnibox histograms
along with a detailed description for each histogram.

For best practices on writing histogram descriptions, see
https://chromium.googlesource.com/chromium/src.git/+/HEAD/tools/metrics/histograms/README.md

Please send CLs to chromium-metrics-reviews@google.com rather than to specific
individuals. These CLs will be automatically reassigned to a reviewer within
about 5 minutes. This approach helps the metrics team to load-balance incoming
reviews. Googlers can read more about this at go/gwsq-gerrit.
-->

<histogram-configuration>

<histograms>

<histogram name="Omnibox.AnswerParseSuccess" enum="BooleanSuccess"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    For each answer received in suggest responses, the number that are
    well-formed and contain all the required elements.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.AnswerParseType" enum="SuggestionAnswerType"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of times each omnibox suggestion answer type (e.g., weather,
    sports score) was received and parsed successfully. Can be normalized with
    the count of emits to Omnibox.SuggestRequest.Success.GoogleResponseTime,
    which counts all successful suggest responses from Google, not just those
    with answers attached. Note that GoogleResponseTime is technically off given
    that it will still count cases where we fail to extract, deserialize, or
    parse the response. But these cases are rare to non-existent.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.BitmapFetchLatency" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-04-23">
<!-- Name completed by histogram_suffixes name="Omnibox.BitmapFetchLatencyCacheSplit" -->

  <owner>manukh@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The time elapsed between the ChromeOmniboxClient requesting a suggestion's
    image to receiving the image. This includes both uncached and cached
    requests. See BitmapFetcher.Fetch and BitmapFetcher.Decode for what
    contributes to uncached images latency; however, the sum of those metrics
    can be greater than this metric as image prefetching begins before the
    ChromeOmniboxClient requests an image.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-03-23">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>asvitkine@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Records the time taken between a keystroke being typed in the omnibox and
    the text being painted. If there are multiple keystrokes before a paint,
    logs the time since the earliest one.

    This duration is composed of three parts:

    a) the time spent processing the initial input event

    b) the time spent for the repaint task to be scheduled on the message loop

    c) the time spent painting the Omnibox

    d) (on views platforms) the time until the pixels are actually composited

    There's a number of breakdown metrics to help diagnose a regression. First,
    Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency.ToPaint measures the combined time of (a)
    and (b). Omnibox.QueryTime2 is a good proxy for just (a). And there's also
    Omnibox.PaintTime that corresponds to (c). We don't have a direct metric for
    (d), but if neither Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency.ToPaint nor
    Omnibox.PaintTime regressed, then the regression must be in (d).

    Note: The semantics of this metric on views platforms changed in M62, as
    previously time (d) was not included in the metric.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency.InsertToPresent" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>asvitkine@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    A refinement of Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency metric. It measures the
    time between the first character insertion in a series that happen during a
    frame, to the time the compositor reports the text was rendered on-screen.
    Compositor-provided timestamps are used for this version of the metric, so
    it is expected to be more accurate: the baseline CharTypedToRepaintLatency
    uses now() from when the subsequent has-processed notification arrives back
    on the UI thread, which may overestimate user-visible latency.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency.PaintToPresent" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>asvitkine@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Records the time between when OnPaint() is called to the time the compositor
    reports pixels were successfully drawn to the screen. This a subset of the
    time reported in Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency.InsertToPresent.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency.ToPaint" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>asvitkine@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Records the time taken between a keystroke being typed in the omnibox and
    the time when we're ready to paint the omnibox. This is a breakdown
    diagnostic metric for Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency, to help diagnose
    regressions in that metric. See that metric's description for more info.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ClipboardSuggestionRemovedAge" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-03-01">
  <owner>gangwu@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>fgorski@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Recorded every time the clipboard suggestion is removed from omnibox
    suggestion list and the system clipboard. The value indicates the estimated
    age of the clipboard.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ClipboardSuggestionShownAge" units="ms"
    expires_after="M93">
  <owner>gangwu@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Recorded every time the omnibox is focussed and recent content from the
    user's clipboard is suggested. The value indicates the estimated age of the
    clipboard. (If Chrome observed the clipboard modification, this age is
    exact. If Chrome did not observe the modification, then it's a conservative
    estimate: the last time Chrome observed a clipboard modification, which is
    certainly older than the current clipboard. If Chrome never observed a
    clipboard modification, no clipboard suggestion is shown, meaning this
    histogram will never be emitted to.)

    Intended to be compared with MobileOmnibox.PressedClipboardSuggestionAge.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ClipboardSuggestionShownNumTimes" units="units"
    expires_after="M93">
  <owner>gangwu@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Recorded every time the omnibox is focussed and a recent content from the
    user's clipboard is suggested. The number emitted is the number of times the
    clipboard content has been suggested within the same session including the
    current time. Thus, the third time it is shown, we'll emit a three to this
    histogram, and this histogram will have previously seen emits of one and
    two. If the clipboard content was the same during a previous run of Chrome
    and this clipboard content was suggested during that run, those impressions
    are not counted. Also, if the clipboard content changes during a particular
    run of Chrome to other content, the omnibox is focused and that clipboard
    content is suggested, then content changes back and Chrome starts suggesting
    the older clipboard content again, the counts start again from scratch.
    Chrome only remembers the number of times the clipboard content was shown
    consecutively.

    This value is useful to compare with the number of times a clipboard
    suggestion has been shown when it is clicked. This value can be obtained
    from OmniboxEvent records in which the selected suggestion is from Clipboard
    provider. In those cases, look in the Clipboard provider's ProviderInfo
    field for |times_returned_results_in_session|. Note that at the time of this
    writing that OmniboxEvent logs aren't recorded in incognito whereas
    histograms are. Thus, the total counts will not be comparable, though the
    distributions should be.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ClipboardSuggestionShownWithCurrentURL"
    enum="BooleanPresent" expires_after="M93">
  <owner>gangwu@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Recorded every time the omnibox is focussed and a recent content from the
    user's clipboard is suggested. The value indicates whether the current URL
    was shown (which would appear above the clipboard suggestion) or was absent
    (which ought to only happen when the omnibox is empty / the user is on the
    NTP).

    On Android, the total count for this histogram can be usefully compared with
    the count of the user action FocusLocation in order to determine the rate at
    which a clipboard suggestion is shown in the omnibox. To determine the same
    rate on iOS, one needs to compare this histogram's count with the sum of the
    user actions MobileFocusedOmniboxOnNtp, MobileFocusedFakeboxOnNtp, and
    MobileFocusedOmniboxNotOnNtp.

    Furthermore, on either platform, this histogram's count can be usefully
    compared with the count in the clipboard bucket of the
    Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.Provider histogram to determine the clickthrough rate
    on these suggestions.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.CutOrCopyAllText" units="count"
    expires_after="2021-01-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of cut or copy commands on all selected text in the omnibox.
    Gathered on desktop platforms (Win, Mac, Linux, Chrome OS).
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.DocumentSuggest.Requests"
    enum="OmniboxDocumentSuggestRequests" expires_after="M88">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>skare@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts the number of document suggest requests the omnibox sent, were
    invalidated, and were completed successfully.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.DocumentSuggest.ResultCount" units="count"
    expires_after="M88">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>skare@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Number of results returned in each document suggestion reply. Logged for
    successful requests where the provider returned a parseable result set.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ElisionConfig" enum="OmniboxElisionConfig"
    expires_after="M88">
  <owner>livvielin@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The state of URL elision in the omnibox, e.g. URL default behavior,
    prevented by context menu option, or prevented by Chrome extension. This
    histogram is recorded the first time ShouldPreventElision is called on
    ChromeLocationBarModelDelegate with an existing profile. This occurs every
    time a browser window is open, including when opening a new profile or
    moving a tab to a new window. This metric measures the percentage of browser
    windows that use each type of elision behavior.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.EnteredKeywordMode2" enum="OmniboxEnteredKeywordMode2"
    expires_after="2021-01-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The new enumeration of how many times users enter keyword hint mode
    &quot;Search ___ for:&quot; and how. Note that we don't recognize the
    changing of the keyword itself as entering keyword mode, if the user never
    left keyword mode e.g. if the user was arrowing around the suggestions, so
    we'll preserve the original keyword mode entry method in this case.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.FocusResultedInNavigation" enum="BooleanNavigated"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>ender@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    This records whether user initiated navigation after focusing the Omnibox
    versus switches focus elsewhere without navigating. This metric includes
    accidental focus-then-losing-focus events, including brief ones. It also
    includes ones in which the user did not type any text or otherwise engage
    with the Omnibox. E.g., the user tabbing through all top Chrome UI controls
    will cause this metric to be recorded. If the user switches focus from the
    Chrome window to another window while the Omnibox is focussed, that also
    counts as a loss of focus.

    This metric is not recorded for the Realbox interactions.

    Recorded every time the Omnibox focus is cleared.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.FocusToEditTime" units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The length of time between when a user focused on the omnibox and first
    modifies the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.FocusToOpenTimeAnyPopupState3" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The length of time between when a user focused on the omnibox and opened an
    omnibox match (which could be what they typed or a suggestion). This is
    recorded regardless of whether the omnibox dropdown (a.k.a. popup) is open.
    It is not recorded if a match is opened without triggering a focus event,
    e.g., when a user drags a URL to the omnibox to navigate.

    To know how common this last condition is, compare the total count of this
    histogram to the total number of omnibox events.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.HoverTime" units="ms" expires_after="M88">
  <owner>estark@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>carlosil@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The time duration that the user hovers the mouse over the omnibox before
    exiting the hover or focusing the omnibox. Whenever the user's mouse enters
    the omnibox, this histogram is recorded when the mouse next exits or the
    omnibox is focused, whichever comes first. The recorded value is a delta
    from a timestamp noted when the user's mouse first entered the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.IconOrFaviconShown" enum="SuggestionIconOrFaviconType"
    expires_after="M83">
  <owner>ender@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-android-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Records suggestions decorated with specific icon or favicon at the time the
    user exited the omnibox. Exiting the omnibox includes navigating (to entered
    text or any suggestion), pressing the system back key, clearing omnibox,
    blanking screen / locking the phone (whether intentionally or due to
    inactivity), or closing the Chrome app. This metric is logged every time the
    omnibox is exited, including when no answer is present in the list of
    suggestions.

    This histogram is related to Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.IconOrFaviconType.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.InputType" enum="OmniboxInputType"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The kind of input the user provided when using the omnibox to go somewhere.
    The type can be misleading. For example if the user typed 'http:/', it gets
    marked as a query because it cannot be opened as a URL even though the user
    probably wanted and selected a URL from the list of suggestions.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.IsPasteAndGo" enum="Boolean"
    expires_after="2021-01-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Whether an omnibox interaction is a paste-and-search/paste-and-go action.
    (This histogram records both of these in the &quot;True&quot; bucket for
    this histogram because both of these are referred to as paste-and-go in the
    code.) These typically involve right-clicking in the omnibox and selecting
    that option from the dropdown.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.IsPopupOpen" enum="Boolean" expires_after="2021-01-30">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Whether the omnibox popup (a.k.a. dropdown) is open at the time the user
    used the omnibox to go somewhere. It can be closed if, for instance, the
    user clicked in the omnibox and hit return to reload the same page. Also,
    because paste-and-search/paste-and-go actions ignore the current content of
    the omnibox dropdown (if it is open) when they happen, we pretend the
    dropdown is closed when logging these.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.JustDeletedText" enum="Boolean"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Whether the user deleted text immediately before selecting an omnibox
    suggestion. This is usually the result of pressing backspace or delete.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.LocalHistoryZeroSuggest.AsyncDeleteTime" units="ms"
    expires_after="M87">
  <owner>mahmadi@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The length of time it takes for the corresponding URLs that would produce a
    deleted match to be queried asynchronously and deleted. Triggered when user
    deletes a local history zero-prefix suggestion.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.LocalHistoryZeroSuggest.SearchTermsExtractedCount"
    units="count" expires_after="M87">
  <owner>mahmadi@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of search terms extracted from the keyword search terms database
    and examined (e.g., sorted) to produce local zero-prefix suggestions.
    Triggered when zero-prefix suggestions are enabled and requested as a result
    of user focus into the Omnibox or the Realbox on the NTP.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.LocalHistoryZeroSuggest.SearchTermsExtractionTime"
    units="ms" expires_after="M87">
  <owner>mahmadi@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The length of time it takes to extract search terms from the keyword search
    terms database and examine (e.g., sort) them to produce local zero-prefix
    suggestions.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.LocalHistoryZeroSuggest.SyncDeleteTime" units="ms"
    expires_after="M87">
  <owner>mahmadi@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The length of time it takes to handle the deletion request for a match and
    to update the list of provider matches synchronously. Triggered when user
    requests to delete a local history zero-prefix suggestion.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.MatchStability.AsyncMatchChange2" units="position"
    expires_after="2021-03-01">
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    This tracks how unstable our matches are due to asynchronous updates.
    Whenever a dropdown position gets asynchronously set to a new match that's
    different from the old match, this histogram logs the index.

    We primarily care the default match, which is logged at index 0. All indices
    matter though, so we track the other indices too. When the number of matches
    changes asynchronously, matches that are removed are considered a
    &quot;change&quot; and logged here. Matches that are appended are less
    disruptive to the user, and are not logged.

    This is because this metric is primarily interested in how many times the
    user could be looking at a match with the intention of selecting it, and
    then it surprisingly goes away.

    Note that merely adding a new asynchronous provider will increase these
    counts. That's intentional. Swapping matches out annoys users, and to avoid
    this, we should do some things like: caching, update coaslescing, update
    deferral until next keystroke, provider timeouts, etc.

    This metric is designed to be normalized by the True count of
    Omnibox.Start.WantAsyncMatches, which will yield the number of match changes
    asynchronously per keystroke or other user gesture.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.MatchStability.AsyncMatchChangedInAnyPosition"
    enum="BooleanChanged" expires_after="2021-03-01">
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    This tracks how unstable our matches are due to asynchronous updates.

    For each asynchronous autocomplete update, this histogram logs whether any
    match in any position has changed. Note: if the only change is new matches
    appended to the end of the list, that does not count as a change, since it's
    not very disruptive to the user.

    This metric is designed to be normalized by the True count of
    Omnibox.Start.WantAsyncMatches, which will yield the number of times any
    match changes asynchronously per keystroke or other user gesture.

    This histogram can be considered a boolean analogue to
    Omnibox.MatchStability.AsyncMatchChange2.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.NumEvents" enum="UsedOmnibox"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of times users used the omnibox to go somewhere.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.NumTypedTerms" units="terms"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of terms in the text the user entered in the omnibox when they
    used the omnibox to go somewhere. Terms are defined by splitting on
    whitespace. All values larger than 6 are recorded in bucket 6.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.OnDeviceHeadSuggest.AsyncQueryTime" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-03-09">
  <owner>cch@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>suggest-2g@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Time it takes for omnibox on device head provider to fulfill the
    asynchronous suggest request.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.OnDeviceHeadSuggest.ResultCount" units="count"
    expires_after="2021-03-09">
  <owner>cch@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>suggest-2g@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of results returned by the on device head model which matches the
    user input. Note all numbers greater than 5 are recorded in bucket 5.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.PaintTime" units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>asvitkine@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Records the time to paint the omnibox contents. This is a subcomponent of
    Omnibox.CharTypedToRepaintLatency. Implemented on desktop platforms.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.Paste" units="count" expires_after="2021-01-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of paste commands on the text in the omnibox. Reported every time
    a paste command is done.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.PasteAndGo" units="count" expires_after="2021-02-07">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of paste-and-go commands on the text in the omnibox. Reported
    every time a paste-and-go command is done.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.PedalShown" enum="SuggestionPedalType"
    expires_after="2021-06-01">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>orinj@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts the type (concept ID) of omnibox pedals shown when the user used the
    omnibox to go somewhere.

    Pedals are a button attached to a search suggestion that either navigate to
    a chrome:// URL or trigger a Chrome action (for example, opening the page
    translation dialog or opening a new window in Incognito mode).

    Note that, while it is uncommon, it is possible for multiple pedals to be
    shown at one time so this can't be used as a count of how many times a pedal
    or pedals were present.

    This histogram is related to Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.Pedal.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ProviderTime2" units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The length of time taken by the named provider&quot;s synchronous pass.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.QueryTime2" units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Time it takes for the omnibox to become responsive to user input after the
    user has typed N characters. This measures the time it takes to start all
    autocomplete providers (but not wait for the asynchronous ones to finish).
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.Search.OffTheRecord" enum="BooleanOffTheRecord"
    expires_after="2021-06-01">
  <owner>rhalavati@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-privacy-core@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    This histogram records the number of searches done from omnibox using
    default search engine on desktop and android devices, sliced based on being
    in regular mode or private modes.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SearchEngineType" enum="OmniboxSearchEngineType"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The type of search engine associated with a match opened from the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SearchProviderMatches" units="units"
    expires_after="2021-01-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of matches returned by SearchProvider. Emitted on every call to
    SearchProvider::Start(), which effectively means every key stroke in the
    omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SelectedPosition" units="position"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The index of the item that the user selected in the omnibox popup (a.k.a.
    dropdown) list. 0 means the inline suggestion shown within the omnibox. This
    is also the same suggestion shown as the top item in the dropdown. The
    second item in the dropdown will be recorded as bucket 1. The selected
    position is always set to 0 when the popup is closed at the time of
    navigation or if the user did a paste-and-search or paste-and-go action.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ShowFullUrlsEnabled" enum="BooleanEnabled"
    expires_after="M88">
  <owner>livvielin@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Tracks whether the context menu option to prevent URL elisions in the
    omnibox is enabled. Recorded when the pref is toggled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.Start.WantAsyncMatches" enum="Boolean"
    expires_after="2021-03-01">
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Whether asynchronous matches are requested. Recorded every time
    AutocompleteController::Start() is called.

    False counts roughly correspond to non-interactive invocations of
    AutocompleteController - like when we are classifying user text as a Search
    or URL.

    True counts roughly correspond to keystrokes or on-focus events, and can be
    used as a normalizer for per-user-gesture metrics.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.AnswerInSuggest"
    enum="SuggestionAnswerOptionalType" expires_after="2021-06-01">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts how often omnibox suggestions are used, and in the case an Answer
    suggestion was selected - records the type of an answer. This histogram is
    useful because there is no distinct suggestion type recorded for answers so
    their use is not recorded by Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.ProviderAndResultType.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.OfferedTabMatch" enum="BooleanOffered"
    expires_after="M93">
  <owner>gangwu@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Measures whether the suggestion that was selected by the user offered a tab
    match. A tab match occurs when the URL specified by the suggestion matches
    the URL navigated to by another tab in the browser, within the margin of our
    URL stripping scheme.

    This metric typically only makes sense with respect to
    Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.OfferedTabMatch. Only recent versions of the browser
    send the metric. Therefore, other metrics may include datapoints not covered
    by this metric (unless one narrows the data by version.)

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.Pedal" enum="SuggestionPedalType"
    expires_after="2021-06-01">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>orinj@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts how often omnibox pedals are used and records the type (concept ID)
    of the pedal used.

    Pedals are a button attached to a search suggestion that either navigate to
    a chrome:// URL or trigger a Chrome action (for example, opening the page
    translation dialog or opening a new window in Incognito mode).

    This histogram is related to Omnibox.PedalShown.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram
    name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.Search.Experimental.NavigationToFirstMeaningfulPaint"
    units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Measures the time from navigation start to first meaningful paint. Only
    recorded for a search query suggestion selected from the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram
    name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.Search.NavigationToFirstContentfulPaint"
    units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Measures the time from navigation start to first contentful paint. Only
    recorded for a search query suggestion selected from the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.SelectedTabMatch"
    enum="BooleanSelected" expires_after="M93">
  <owner>gangwu@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Measures whether the suggestion that was selected by the user offered a tab
    match and specifically that the user chose the tab match over normal
    navigation. A tab match occurs when the URL specified by the suggestion
    matches the URL navigated to by another tab in the browser, within the
    margin of our URL stripping scheme. By selecting the tab match, the browser
    simply switches focus to the matching tab.

    This metric typically only makes sense with respect to
    Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.OfferedTabMatch. Only recent versions of the browser
    send the metric. Therefore, other metrics may include datapoints not covered
    by this metric (unless one narrows the data by version.)

    This metric should be stricly less than
    Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.OfferedTabMatch, and is typically used to discover
    the percentage of offered tab matches that the user accepts.

    In M-74 and earlier, this was only recorded if the user had no incognito
    windows open. In M-75 and later, it records all omnibox interactions
    regardless, in order to be consistent with how user actions and histograms
    are handled.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram
    name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.URL.Experimental.NavigationToFirstMeaningfulPaint"
    units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Measures the time from navigation start to first meaningful paint. Only
    recorded for a URL suggestion selected from the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestionUsed.URL.NavigationToFirstContentfulPaint"
    units="ms" expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Measures the time from navigation start to first contentful paint. Only
    recorded for a URL suggestion selected from the omnibox.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestRequest.Failure.GoogleResponseTime" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-03-09">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>cch@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The time elapsed between the sending of a suggest request to Google until
    the time the request was returned with status==failed. Ignores requests that
    were canceled before being returned.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestRequest.Success.GoogleResponseTime" units="ms"
    expires_after="2021-03-09">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>cch@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    The time elapsed between the sending of a suggest request to Google until
    the time the request was returned with status==success. Ignores requests
    that were canceled before being returned.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestRequest.Success.PrefetchImagesCount"
    units="count" expires_after="2021-04-09">
  <owner>manukh@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The number of images prefetched by the search provider on retrieving a
    successful search response.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.SuggestRequests" enum="OmniboxSuggestRequests"
    expires_after="2021-03-09">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>cch@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts about the number of suggest requests the omnibox sent, invalidated,
    and replies received.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ToggleSuggestionGroupId.Off" enum="SuggestionGroupId"
    expires_after="2021-08-01">
  <owner>mahmadi@google.com</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts the number of times a suggestion group ID is prevented form appearing
    in the results. This is recorded when the user hides a set of grouped
    suggestions, such as proactive zero-suggest, in the omnibox UI using the
    control in the grouped suggestions' header.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ToggleSuggestionGroupId.On" enum="SuggestionGroupId"
    expires_after="2021-08-01">
  <owner>mahmadi@google.com</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts the number of times a suggestion group ID is permitted to appear in
    the results. This is recorded when the user makes a set of previously hidden
    grouped suggestions, such as proactive zero-suggest, visible in the omnibox
    UI using the control in the grouped suggestions' header.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.URLNavigationScheme" enum="NavigationScheme"
    expires_after="2021-06-30">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    The scheme of the destination URL for the selected omnibox suggestion. This
    could be a what-you-typed suggestion (if the user fully typed a URL), an
    inline autocompletion, or something in the dropdown, anything as long as
    it's a URL navigation, not a search query. Excludes omnibox URL navigations
    that are effectively reloads as well as cut-and-pastes of URLs. Also does
    not take into account any redirects that destination URL may do before
    finally serving a page. In other words, it's the scheme of the first request
    in a possible chain.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.UserTextCleared" enum="OmniboxUserTextCleared"
    expires_after="M85">
  <owner>kenjibaheux@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts the number of times that the user text is cleared. IME users are
    sometimes in the situation that IME was unintentionally turned on and failed
    to input latin alphabets (ASCII characters) or the opposite case. In that
    case, users may delete all the text and the user text gets cleared. This
    histogram helps us estimate how often this scenario happens.

    Note that since we don't currently correlate &quot;text cleared&quot; events
    with IME usage, this also captures many other cases where users clear the
    text; though it explicitly doesn't log deleting all the permanent text as
    the first action of an editing sequence (see comments in
    OnAfterPossibleChange()).
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.WarmupTime" units="ms" expires_after="M85">
  <owner>etienneb@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Time it takes for the omnibox to process the first user interaction after
    startup. This measures the time it takes to start all autocomplete providers
    and their initialisation steps. This metric may be recorded twice as there
    is the normal omnibox path and also the &quot;classify text&quot; path to
    the autocomplete system.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ZeroSuggest.Eligible.OnFocusV2"
    enum="ZeroSuggestEligibleOnFocus" expires_after="2021-01-31">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Whether the user has settings configured so that the current page URL can be
    sent to the suggest server to request contextual suggestions. For example,
    this is only supported for users who have Google as their default search
    engine (unmodified version of Google), have search suggest enabled, are
    signed-in and syncing without a custom passphrase, and don't have an
    incognito window open. There are other criteria too. Recorded on focus in
    the omnibox if there is default search provider and we've constructed a
    suggest URL.

    Some additional guidelines: if an incognito window is open, all focus events
    will go into the &quot;generally ineligible&quot; bucket. Likewise, if the
    current page is a search results page, we don't allow contextual suggestions
    either so focus events on those pages go in the &quot;generally
    ineligible&quot; bucket. The difference between &quot;eligible&quot; and
    &quot;generally eligible but not this time&quot; depends only the properties
    of the current URL.

    Recorded regardless of whether contextual or non-contextual zero suggest is
    currently enabled on the user's platform. However, if zero suggest (in all
    forms) is entirely disabled, the user will be perpetually ineligible.

    This histogram captures all scenarios that are generally ineligible for zero
    suggest suggestions (including incognito mode), and reports eligibility for
    suggestions even if kOmniboxPopupShortcutIconsInZeroState is enabled
    (meaning: suggestions are not shown, but current URL is eligible).
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ZeroSuggest.Eligible.OnProfileOpen"
    enum="BooleanSupported" expires_after="2021-01-31">
  <owner>mpearson@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>jdonnelly@chromium.org</owner>
  <summary>
    Whether the user has settings configured so that the current page URL could
    be sent to the suggest server to request contextual suggestions. For
    example, this is only supported for users who have Google as their default
    search engine (unmodified version of Google), have search suggest enabled,
    and are signed-in and syncing without a custom passphrase. There are other
    criteria too. Recorded on profile open. Note that opening an incognito
    window (if none are currently open under the given profile) counts as
    opening a new profile.

    Some additional guidelines: unlike Omnibox.ZeroSuggest.Eligible.OnFocus,
    because this is recorded on profile open, users cannot be declared
    ineligible because they have an incognito window open (it's impossible to
    have an incognito window open for a given profile at the time of profile
    open) and also cannot be declared ineligible because the user is viewing a
    search results page. (We test this on-profile-open using an arbitrary URL.)

    Recorded regardless of whether contextual or non-contextual zero suggest is
    currently enabled on the user's platform. However, if zero suggest (in all
    forms) is entirely disabled, the user will be perpetually ineligible.
  </summary>
</histogram>

<histogram name="Omnibox.ZeroSuggestRequests" enum="OmniboxZeroSuggestRequests"
    expires_after="2021-01-31">
  <owner>ender@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>tommycli@chromium.org</owner>
  <owner>chrome-omnibox-team@google.com</owner>
  <summary>
    Counts about the number of zero suggest requests (requests for suggestions
    when the user has focused but not modified the omnibox) the omnibox sent,
    invalidated, and replies received.
  </summary>
</histogram>

</histograms>

</histogram-configuration>
